Check tech check. One, two.
Good evening
everyone. I would like to call to order
the April 29th, 2025 meeting of
Lancaster City Council. A few reminders
and announcements for this evening.
Please take a moment to silence your
phones and devices if you haven't done
so already. This meeting and its
participants are being
recorded. Bill number three uh needed to
be readvertised and will not be taken up
this evening. It will be on our agenda
for May 13th as well as the Lafayette
Day's resolution has also been scheduled
for that date. Anyone addressing city
council this meeting uh during public
comment period should please do so
clearly and directly into the microphone
uh to be heard. We are working with some
different equipment this evening
obviously uh to ensure that we can
proceed and ensure that we have video
record of this meeting. I'd like to
commend our city staff for their hard
work in making this possible and finding
a quick solution after last week's
technical failure. For those who have
registered in advance, Mr. Harris will
be reading your name and block of block
or municipality of residents into the
record. For all other commenters, please
begin your comments with your name and
block or municipality of residents. For
the record, public comment is limited to
three minutes per speaker. To keep time
this evening, I will be using this light
in front of me. It will turn green when
your time begins. It will blink yellow
when there is one minute remaining and
it will blink red when three minutes has
been exhausted. I appreciate uh everyone
uh making sure that everyone has equal
time in advance. And now for all of
those who are willing and able, please
rise for the pledge of
allegiance to the flag of the United
States of America and to the standy.
Mr. Harris, would you please call the
role of members? Yes, Madam President.
Mr.
here. Mr. Roy here. Mr. Cle here. Miss
Craig here. Miss Diaz here. Mr. H here.
President Baker here.
We'll now move to the approval of the
minutes of the April 8th, 2025 meeting
of council.
Motion to approve. Second. We have a
motion and a second. Are there any
council comments on the minutes?
Hearing none. Mr. Harris. Mr. M. I. Mr.
Royo I Mr. Cle I Mr. Craig I Miss Diaz I
Mr. H I President B I
I believe we have no proclamations,
honors, awards and resolutions of
recognition this evening. Is that
correct, Mr. Harris? That is correct,
Madam President. All right. We will then
proceed to our first public comment
period. I'll just make a note that we
don't have a legislative agenda this
evening. So this meeting will consist
solely of public comment. The first
period is reserved for residents who
have contacted the city clerk prior to
the meeting to request the opportunity
to address council. They'll be taken in
the order that the request was received.
Again, duration of comments is limited
to three minutes per speaker and we'll
begin by reading your name and block or
municipality of residence into the
record and then you can begin. Mr.
Harris, if you'd call the speakers. Yes,
Madam President. First, we have uh Edrey
Dennison of the 700 block of South Line
Street.
Is Edrey Dennis
here? I'll call the name at the end just
in case. We'll continue to the next.
Next is Shannon Butler of the 300 block
of Howard Avenue.
I don't see Miss Butler here at the
moment. We'll continue. I will recall
these names at the end.
Next is Irene Grievous of Lancaster
Township.
Miss Grievous, good evening. And if you
could just make sure that the green
light is on by pressing the button on
the
microphone. Green light is not. Oh, this
one's red. I'm so sorry. A red light is
what you're looking for. There it is.
Thank
you. Good evening. My name is Irene
Grievous on the 400 block of West End
Avenue. There has been a lot of outrage
recently over the discrimination
allegedly targeted at Counselor Diaz.
and let's be honest, used as political
propaganda to advance Keller uh
counselor's Oral's memorial um memorial
campaign. This outrage is not only
hypocritical but completely
contradictory to the same types of
discrimination that has been raised in
this very chambers for years only to be
ignored by this council.
Let me ask all of you, where was this
outrage when councelor Beay stood
silently as Mayor Sarra slandered and
persecuted me in the August of 2024
simply for doing everything in my power
for over three and a half years to get
my property out of an unlawful
condemnation during a housing crisis
that displaced four separate families.
Number two, where is the outrage when
mayor used taxpayers dollars to
fabricate claims of lead poisoning in
one of my properties to justify the
city's illegal actions? Those
allegations weren't just false. They
were weaponized to destroy lives and
reputations. Number three, where was the
outrage when the city revoked all of my
rental licenses without due process,
risking the displacement of over 50
people from their homes that they're
running from me? These are human beings,
families, children, and you allowed all
this to happen in silence. And where is
the outrage when other property owners
like Mr. Zaki of
247 253 North Queen Street stood in this
very podium and said there is no justice
or democracy. You we have to buy
justice. We all have to buy justice.
Justice is not free which it should be.
He's not the only one. There are so many
of us disappropriately
targeted. while those with personal ties
in this administration profit from the
suffering that many people and residents
are facing. This is discrim this
discrimination is real. It is documented
and the lawsuits pile up including mine
as many of you already know. You all
continue to deflect and deny. Shame on
all of
you. Janet Diaz was the only one who
ever publicly apologized for this
administration actions. And now she's
being scapegoed for political gain of
Jamie
Ario whose campaign promises more of the
same bureaucratic pol uh politics that
have failed the cities miserably. If you
want to talk about discrimination, let's
talk about discrimination with actions,
not just empty words. Thank you. Thank
you, Miss Grievous.
Mr. Harris.
Next speaker is uh Kevin P at the 400
block of um South Queen Street.
Good evening. Good evening.
Good evening to everyone and God bless
everyone who is here today. I'm uh
Reverend Kevin Polite, the lead pastor
of Souls Church Incorporated of 415
South uh Queen Street in Lancaster City.
I want to thank you for the opportunity
to address the board today in regards to
the property at 843 Fairmont Street, the
closed fire station number six building.
It is also a great privilege for me to
be able to speak in this chamber where
my uncle Nelson Polite SE senior served
for many years as the president of city
council. Soul's church incorporated is a
committee focused church a church that
is expanding the kingdom of God one soul
at a time. Soul's Church started 17
months ago going from home to home
having
services and after four months we were
given the opportunity to rent a building
on South Queen Street. We pulled
together, prepared the building,
continued with the upkeep and the
financial responsibilities that came
along with renting a commercial
building. We started getting excited
about new faces that were showing up.
but soon realized that parking was a
major issue. Though many visitors
enjoyed worship and fellowship, they
were not willing to continue to drive
around the blocks three to four times
for parking. They simply went somewhere
else. We made arrangements with
community action program and but a half
a half a mile
walk but a half a mile walk became a
challenge that most people still weren't
willing to make especially in the winter
months. Our next challenge is a
substantial rent increase that we are
looking at for the next year. So today I
appeal to you on two levels about the
fireh hall. Uh in the natural we realize
that this is a great value both
financially and the use that could be
used and benefited from the property. in
the spiritual aspect, which is what God
has called me to. I move in faith and
obedience to God and see Soul's church
continue to grow. So, in faith, I stand
before you today and request that the
building be donated to Souls Church
Incorporated so we can turn it into a
church.
The Bible says, "You do not receive
because you do not know how to ask with
the right
intentions." Our intentions are to
expand the kingdom of God and be a
blessing to the community. I will close
with
this. As a young teen, I wanted to be a
fireman to serve to save lives. I later
took the agility test and exam and
passed them both. While on the waiting
list, God called me to the ministry to
save lives. How fitting would it be for
me to continue to save lives inside of a
firehouse and both of my dreams be
fulfilled at the same time? Thank you
very much. Thank you.
Our next speaker, Mr. Harris. Next
speaker is Fabian Martinez of the 400
block of South I'm sorry, Fabian
Martinez of the 400 block of South Queen
Street. Mr. Martinez, good evening. Good
evening. God God bless you guys. So, my
name is Fabian Martinez, a local youth
pastor and a children's pastor with
Souls Church in Langster City, the
southern side of Langster City at 415
South Queen Street. First and foremost,
I want to look at all you guys, all of
you on the panel, and say thank you for
all you all you do. I've been a
Lancasterian. that topic, that term
doesn't get used a lot around here, but
for 35 years, and I do appreciate both
sides on what you do, um, and everything
that you do to serve the community well.
Um, as as a product of the school
district of Langston being here, um, I
can honestly say thank you for all that
you do. I am here today to share about
Soul's Church and the possible petition
for obtaining the empty building at 843
Fremont Street, Langster, Pennsylvania
17603. We all know the danger of an
empty building and we know what that
entails. So that is why we look forward
to occupying it. Um, so church, we are
looking to help provide hope in Christ
to help bring peace,
restoration, love, grace, resources, and
a solution alongside of policemen,
women, firefighters, officials, other
local nonprofit organizations, and all
of you to help truly make this city a
better place and a safe place. If this
location is obtained, this is what we
can and promise to do. reach the
community, love in the community, and
coming alongside of them by doing the
following. Reaching people with the hope
of Christ, teaching them accurate
biblical principles, which whether we
agree on or not, we know when we
actually do the best that we can to
follow those principles, we can all
agree it does organically produce a
better life. Also, releasing people to
go reach and make a difference in this
world, nation, state, and city of
Langster for Christ on all levels.
This is also what we can do. Our hearts
are to be sitting where people sit. Meet
people in their needs. Producing highly
effective outreaches all over that side
of Lancaster with the goal of helping
citizens with their day-to-day needs.
Reach the homeless. Reach those who
suffer from addiction. Help with finding
furniture, handing out blankets, gloves,
shoes, clothing need, family vouchers.
bringing families that are in need of
food into the church once again and
being able to send them home filled up
in two aspects, the spiritual and also
the physical. Also working very closely
to provide resources and solution for
our children and youth in Langster
City. Let's truly ask ourselves here.
How many of us truly have kids? I have
three.
There's a concern here that many people
don't address and that's where my heart
is to reach the youth of this city. In
ages 10 to 14, whether we all like to
agree to it or not, there's accidents
being the first form of death and
illnesses being the third. But the
second one is the one that concerns me
because I try to take my life once upon
a time. The second way we are losing our
children and our youth today from 10 to
14 is simply suicide. something has to
be done. We are willing to do this
alongside of all of you, everyone here,
to be able to give them a better and
safer life and and in many other o other
things. We're losing them to guns,
drugs, and so much more. But here we are
together alongside of you guys to say
would you could you possibly give us
this building so we can come alongside
of this community as well as you guys
and give us a better western langster
side blessings. Thank you Mr. Martinez.
Mr. Harris our next speaker for this
period. Yes, Madam President. The next
speaker is Jessica Lopez of Lancaster
City.
Miss Lopez, good evening.
Good evening, Jessica Lopez, Lancaster
City. First, let me start by saying hi.
I hope everyone is having good evening.
Um, I truly do appreciate the echoed
cause for the for council member Diaz to
resign
and the outcry of accountability.
Excuse you, I'm talking. Could we please
have order in the room for a speaker?
Thank Like I said, I completely
appreciate the echo calls for
accountability coming from some of our
council members and our community
members following the comments made
towards Councilman Ahmed and the
outpouring of social media comments that
have come to light from Councilwoman
Janet Diaz, who was not hacked, that
were blatantly fear-mongering and
Islamophobic comments. Our Islamic
community members deserve protection and
support. If Councilwoman Diaz was making
anti-Semitic comments, would this even
be a
question? If she claimed Christians
raised their children in hate to be
killers, would the same people still
support
her? Islam is a beautiful religion
practiced and followed by a diverse
array of people. To claim Janet Diaz is
not Islamophobic, prejudice, and
xenophobic is blatantly a lie. The
religion of Islam is predominantly black
and brown. So you derive what you want
from that. But let me say while no one's
trying to change Councilwoman's Diaz's
views or attack her personally in any
way. We are here to say that this is not
becoming of anyone claiming to be a
representation of us, the residents, not
just Lancaster City, but the people of
the Southeast who work alongside a blend
and array of people.
Excuse me, I'm still talking. Folks in
the room, please.
But where we do need that accountability
from her and yes, from our mayor and
from you because you had your own issues
like everybody else. So, where we do
need accountability, let's not get lost
in what actually brought us here. an
attack on our youth, our black and brown
kids, because that's what we really came
here for, accountability for our
children who were traumatized and
attacked by our officers. They're now
being prosecuted harshly in retaliation
for their
cries. This situation and the failures
in this situation doesn't belong to one
individual. It's the failures of our
safety committee, the police department,
the mayor's office, and this city to
protect and serve their village. So,
yes, while Janet is on her way out,
when she loses this disgusting campaign
she's running, cuz I said what I said,
we will have order during the meeting.
Everyone will get their and the new
mayor takes Denine's seat.
I pray that this community that's
worried about all the wrong
things, learns how to make bike policy
accessible and prioritizes our children
because I came in here for one specific
reason and y'all turned it into this
Janet
show. So, while they're trying to make
it seem as if somebody's in some queue
to take down Janet, she did that
herself. So, I'm sorry. You put your
eggs in the wrong basket. Miss Lopez,
thank you.
[Applause]
Before we proceed, I just want to remind
everybody in the room that we we will
have decorum in council chambers. It's
called the polite council chambers. It's
named after someone who used to serve in
this room. But I would also like to
think that it it also echoes the respect
that we all
deserve. Everyone sitting out here on
the day equally. Okay. So, everyone will
get their their time to speak. I do
appreciate the emotions are high, but we
need to not be yelling out of turn. So,
thank you for helping us keep order
during the meeting. Mr. Harris, our next
speaker. Yes, Madam President. Our next
speaker is Kenneth Miller of the 300
block of Beaver Street. Is Mr. Miller
here?
I do not see I'll recall these names at
the end. Our next speaker, Mr. Harris is
Ivan Aosta of the 800 block of Island
Avenue. It's Mr. Aosta here. I do not
see him. I'll recall these names at the
end. Uh our next speaker, Mr. Harris.
Next speaker is Aaron Dixon of the 500
block of North Street.
Can we please have order in the room?
Thank
you. Good evening, Miss Dixon.
Good
evening. I just wanted to start off by
saying it's an honor to be in this room.
This is my first time being here after
the chamber has been named after my
grandfather Nelson Polite Senior. Um and
I live on his in his property, our
Polite Estate in the 500 block of North
Street. Um I came this evening to make a
few remarks regarding the um calls for
the resignation of Councilwoman Janet
Diaz. I have known Janet and worked with
her for eight years. Uh during that
time, I've only known her to be a
champion for the residents of this city.
And as she stated, she works for every
resident of the city, whether they voted
for her or not, including homeless
immigrants to the city and just regular
everyday folks. Not only has her
commitment to all residents been
absolute, the people of this city
continue to have faith in her abilities
to lead and have sent her with a mandate
not once but twice by electing her to
this body. And I know that if she were
on the ballot again, she would be
elected a third time to this council
because she has earned the confidence of
the voters of this city. Janet was the
only counselor that stood up and spoke
out when I several years ago reached out
to the current administration regarding
a parking project idea that we had
worked on and formulated with SAKA to
help with parking concerns that the
residents of the southeast raised during
the parking authorities study conducted
several years ago. We used our own funds
to pay for and commission plans for a
surface parking lot that would have
benefited all the residents of the
southeast. At that time, the project was
quoted at a cost of around
$100,000, and it would have beautified
the neighborhood, provided secure off-
streetet parking to southeast residents,
and addressed storm water runoff
concerns. When I had read in the paper
that our city was receiving over 39.5
million in ARPA funds, 10 million of
which was being earmarked for
neighborhood projects, I reached out to
the department of neighborhood
engagement and unfortunately I was
unable to get a response or even an
acknowledgement to our request for a
meeting. After two years of trying on my
own, councelor Diaz reached out on our
behalf, and it was only due to her
resilience and persistence that we were
able to finally get a meeting with the
administration regarding the Southeast
parking project. When Miss Diaz worked
on our behalf for city services, she was
not concerned about my race, my
political affiliation, that I was a
woman, she reached out on our behalf
because it was the right thing to do.
And she fights for what is right. and
what is right is not always the popular
thing to do. But all the years that I've
known her, she continues to be resilient
among all the attacks and false
narratives that are put out against her
character. And frankly, um, you have to
be very strong person to overcome all
that she has done and been through as a
member of this body. We all know from
her record that Miss Diaz is not a
racist, a xenophobe to the rim, or islam
or Islamophobic.
Nor has she all of a sudden developed
this deeprooted hatred for any group of
people. That whole narrative being
pushed by certain people is absurd and
false and has
conveniently been orchestrated against
her as she seeks higher office in this
city. Miss Diaz has the right to defend
herself against anyone who oversteps her
boundaries to voice her opinion on
matters before this body to speak up and
speak out against injustice and to vote
her conscience. In conclusion, I'd like
a little leeway. Miss Diaz, I want to
thank you for your dedication and
service for all the residents of this
city. We support you a thousand%. You
have the right to be here. You have the
right to serve out your term and the
majority of the residents of this city
have confidence in you. We have reached
three minutes. And just remember, when
the enemy attacks, respectfully, Miss
Dixon, we have reached three minutes.
And thank you. And I would appreciate
the same leeway that others were given.
Thank you. I've given everybody about 20
seconds of leeway in this meeting. I
didn't get that same leeway as other
individuals, but thank you and I
appreciate the opportunity to speak
before you. Thank you, Mr. Harris. Our
next speaker. Yes, Madam President. Our
next speaker is
one one moment. Mr. Harris, please,
everyone in the room, this please
understand that I am trying my best to
navigate the situation this evening.
Everyone has been given about 20 seconds
of leeway on their three minutes. Okay,
I'm trying to be fair as possible. Let
everyone finish their thoughts, but I do
want to make sure that everyone gets
approximately equal time as best as
possible. I have no way to shut off
microphone, nor do I wish to do so for
anyone speaking this evening. So, please
let's proceed respectfully. Mr. Harris,
our next speaker. Yes, Madam President.
Our next speaker is Clarita Clarita Cruz
of Leapor Drive.
Miss
Cruz. No. Okay. Okay. Next is John Cardi
of Eert Township,
Mr. Cardi. Good evening. Good evening.
Good evening, everyone. My name is John
Cardi. I stand before you, a tarnished
man. That's right. I have made bad
decisions in the past, and I've paid the
penance for them. As my friend,
Councilwoman Diaz's loudest accuser has,
and is no different. She too has a past
in the room. She too has a past and paid
the penance.
Before one goes throwing stones in one's
house, one should make sure one doesn't
live in a glass
house. Where my friend Councilwoman Diaz
differs from myself and her loudest
accuser is that Janice Janet Diaz wakes
up every morning to serve her community.
She goes out of her way every day to
make her community a better place for
everyone to live. That's been her whole
objective. And she inspires people to
aspire to do better for themselves and
the community. She wants people from
this community to elevate themselves
into elected offices. And there's
nothing wrong with that. And it doesn't
matter to her their religious background
or their ethnic background or race or
gender. It just doesn't matter to her.
It just she just wants people from the
local area to get elevated to an elected
office. And there is nothing wrong with
that. Now, now in a perfect world, is
that how it works? No. But her saying
that and her desiring that is not
malicious and it is certainly not
racist. So we need to rein that
[Applause]
in. Couple years ago I was in a strike
line. I remember Janet Diaz there. I
don't remember anybody else on the
panel. Not one of you. Not one of you
were on the strike line with us. Janet
Diaz was she was walking with us right
there. Right there with us. Where were
you all? Where were you? You want to be
mayor? Where were you for the people?
Where were you? You were absent.
She's standing up for us. Are you? I
yield.
Thank you, sir.
[Applause]
Mr. Harris, our next speaker. Next
speaker is Daryl Legacy. the 100 block
of North Mary Street.
Good evening.
Hi. Uh my name is Daryl, 100 block of
the North Mary Street. Um I'm just here
today to sort of distill down um the
question about councelor Diaz's
comments. So either you believe that she
when she didn't respond for a week
claimed she hadn't seen it, then claimed
she was hacked, then claimed it was a
teenage family member, which I think
strains the bonds of credibility. But
maybe maybe that happened. Okay, you
either have to believe that or you have
to believe that either she did post
hateful, racist or islamophobic or both
comments that she really does believe or
or this is the best case, she posts
inflammatory rhetoric on social media
knowing that it might be
misunderstood. Those are the three
options. That's it. And if you believe
either of these two, then that makes her
a liar.
So, it is not my it is not her policies
that has me here asking for her to step
down. It is her rhetoric. When you
search Lancaster, Pennsylvania, and you
look at the news articles that come up,
guess what? The top two things are
police overuse of force and these
comments. Is that what we want Lancaster
to be known for around the country and
around the world?
If you believe that she really was
hacked, and maybe that's possible, she
has the worst password security of
anybody that I've ever met. This is the
second time she has claimed to be
hacked, right? Use a password manager.
Okay, if that's what's really happening.
So, either she is is negligent about her
own social media or she is a liar. Those
are the only two options
here. And I actually would be super
happy to see one of her supporters up
here instead of her. It isn't her
policies. It isn't her work for people.
It is what she posts online and what
that says about Lancaster, Pennsylvania.
And I hope everybody here thinks about
that.
Thank you.
Our next speaker, Mr. Harris. Next
speaker is uh David Miller Glick of the
first block of Hager Street. Thank you.
Good evening, Mr. Miller Glick.
Good evening.
We expect a lot out of our neighbors to
live Lancasterian values of justice,
leadership, and being a welcoming
community to all. We expect even more of
our elected officials. And Councilwoman
Janet Diaz has not been holding up to
that standard. She has an established
pattern of bigotry and personal attacks,
especially towards our black and Muslim
neighbors neighbors. Folks in the room,
order. We will have order during this
meeting. Thank you. Please proceed.
Especially towards our black and Muslim
neighbors that she has been proud to
display on social media. Most recently,
councelor Diaz attacked counselor
Ahmed's identity as a refugee and in Mr.
Miller Glick, please pardon me for just
a moment. Folks in the room, I do not
want to have to make this announcement
again. Everyone who is speaking out of
turn, please can we have some order? If
you have side conversations, you can
take them out of the room. Please
proceed. My apologies. That's okay. I'm
just finding my spot.
Most recently, Councelor Diaz attacked
Counselor Ahmed's identity as a refugee
and insinuated that he was incapable of
holding out office because of her
because of his background. Her racism,
xenophobia, and islamophobia are not the
representation that Lancastrians
deserve. For these reasons, we join our
co coalition partners, Lancaster DSA and
Black Voter Outreach Network, in calling
Janet Diaz to resign from Lancaster City
Council. However, the rise of Janet Diaz
and figures like her did not happen in a
vacuum. They are very there are very
real and justified feelings of lack of
representation in our communities. Our
elected officials continue to ignore the
suffering of our communities, offering
only performative platitudes with little
political risk, commitment, or policy
change behind them. Janet Diaz has found
great success thanks to this climate of
false promises. She co-opts populist
messaging with a regressive vision of
exclusion and
scapegoating. Racist racist politicians
like Councilwoman Diaz would never have
attain obtained so much credibility if
the rest of our elected leaders took
action along with their hollow
words. We look forward to working with
our elected officials to pass
legislation that betters the lives of
our neighbors, families, and loved ones.
We also promise to hold our elected
leaders accountable when they fail us.
Such accountability will continue to be
necessary beyond Janet Diaz's tenure in
power and Lancaster stands up will be
there to see it through. Thank you.
Thank you.
Our next speaker, Mr. Harris.
Yes, Madam President. Our next speaker
is Shandra Demo of East Lampir Township.
Good evening. Good evening everyone.
Hello. Good evening everyone. My name is
Shandra Deal. Thank you for coming here
today. I'm standing here today not just
as a support of Janet Diaz, but as
someone that knows her through her hard
work and her lifelong commitment to this
city and its people. When my people were
getting deported, she was the first
person that came to my mind and we
reached out to her. She gave my
community full of Hindus, Muslims, and
Buddhists, refugees, so much hope. She
has been there for the community through
everything for the past eight years that
I've known her. Please give me some
respect while I'm speaking. Thank you.
Lately, lately, folks in the room,
please. False accusations have been
thrown at Janet claiming that she's
racist. Let me be absolutely clear.
Nothing could be further from the truth.
Janet has spent her whole life lifting
up communities, especially communities
of color, veterans, single mothers, and
the homeless because she believes in
service over division and action over
empty words. Janet knows this city. She
did not just show up when it was time to
run for office. She's been here walking
through these neighborhoods, listening
to people's stories, their hurt, their
fight for years and years, and I know
she will continue to do
that. And we believe in you. She has
fought for single mothers, making sure
they have resources, opportunities, and
hope. She has stood there for
communities of color, not just in words,
but in policies and in programs and in
presence. And I can't say that for a lot
of
people. Janet comes from a family of
veterans, a family that knows about
sacrifice, service, and honor. She
carries those values with her every
single day. And I see that as someone
that knows her
personally. She's also a proud feminist,
a champion of women's rights and
equality. and the idea that every woman
deserves a chance to lead, to thrive,
and to be
respected. Jennet Diaz is for the
people. Not just you and me, but for all
people. She's a divi. She's not a
divider. She's a unifier. She's not
fueled by hate. She's powered by hope,
compassion, and an unbreakable love for
this community. In a time when policies
is filled with noise, distraction, and
negativity, Janet Diaz stays focused on
what really, really matters. Helping
those in need, fighting for justice, and
building a city where everyone, no
matter their race, gender, their
background, have a seat at her table.
And she will always make sure of
that. Her record is clear and her
actions speak louder than any rumor. and
the truth is stronger than any lie that
will ever be thrown out at her. I am
proud to stand with um Jenny Diaz today.
Not just me, but the community I have
brought here
Miss De Mo. We have we have reached the
past three minutes. She is a fighter, a
servant, and a true leader for all of
us. Thank you. Thank you,
Mr. Harris. Our next speaker, next
speaker is ACL Austin from East Lamp
here,
Miss Alustin. Ah, thank you.
Good evening. Good evening. Asalam
alaikum.
Um, is the correct answer. Um, my name
is Asa Austin. Um, first let me just say
uh I am a mother, a grandmother, a poet
and local educator. I have children who
live in this community with their
children. I have worked in this
community since I was 14 years old. So I
can tell you that I am
um I am a huge part of this community
and I know a lot about what is happening
around me. Uh, I moved here when I was
two years old and that would be back
dating back to like 1979. So, I've been
here for a long time. Um, I only left
briefly for college. Came back two
years. I came left two years while I was
married and came right back because like
my mother, I believe that this is a
great community full of diversity and
such a great community to raise and
nurture children in. That's what I still
continue to do. I was also the poet who
um wrote co-wrote with my son Sir
Dominique Jordan the poem for this
city's Junth flag
reason. I stand here representing myself
and many Muslim women who agree with
me. I attempted to speak to Mrs. Diaz on
Saturday. Correct. She had a chance to
apologize.
She chose to deflect and blame everyone
else. Even go as going as far as adding
an intercessor to vouch for her. That
person further offended me. As a Muslim,
not once did you apologize even after.
As a public
official,
you must recognize and be more aware of
what you were doing
insane, especially because you took an
oath and are a representation of all of
the people that you were servicing. The
number of residents who look like me and
share my way of life, they're definitely
on the rise in this area.
Many people who work in the fields that
I work in, they can see it so
clearly. I walk into the schools, the
children are so happy that they finally
see a Muslim woman teaching them. To me,
that's
amazing. The school district of
Lancaster just hired their first Muslim
principal. That says
enough. To be clear, be very
clear. Contrary to what you posted on
your social media and contrary to what
you may believe, Muslim women do have
rights in Islam. We do. It's in the
Quran. And I have to say this, you I do
not disrespect everyone. So, please do
not disrespect me. Thank you, Miss Olen.
Uh, we've just reached past three
minutes. if we could do your final
thoughts. Okay, I'll finish it up. Thank
you. You are responsible for what you
post on social media, so just be aware
of that. And I think you do owe Muslim
women an apology. Thank you. Thank you,
Mr. Harris. Our next speaker. Yes, Madam
President. Next is Sandra Rosario of
Washington.
Miss Rosario. Good evening.
Good evening. Thank
you. First of all, I want to thank you,
council members. Um, I realize that you
have a tough job. Some do it better than
others. Some go out of their way, some
do not.
last year or the year before, I believe
it was a year before, there was a
situation going on in the city school
district and I had reached out to some
leaders. I had also reached out to Mr.
Aoyo. He not only didn't want to take my
call, he didn't return my call. He
didn't respond to any messages or phone
calls. I reached out to him multiple
times and he completely ignored me. And
it was a pressing issue and it was
something that it wasn't hey this is
what I want you to do but hey I want you
to hear me out and think about this and
let's have a dialogue and I he was never
I was never recognized on the contrary I
reached out to Miss Diaz immediately she
reached out now I no longer live in the
city I lived in the city for almost all
my life I have family members that live
in the city so I'm very concerned about
things that happen in the city I drive
through the city all the time. I have
called Miss Diaz and Miss Diaz has lent
an a lending ear. Not only that, she
actually and again it wasn't for her to
take up my point of view of the
situation that was occurring in the
school district, but for her to show her
presence and to take an opinion and she
did on her own. It wasn't mine. It
wasn't what I was thinking about
sharing, but she shared her own thoughts
and she responded. That's the kind of
person that she is. She also looks out
for other people outside of the city
because that's the kind of caring
person. Now, city members, city council
members, you have a homelessness issue,
a serious homelessness is issue. You
have a housing issue. You have a drug
addiction issue. What are you doing?
Focus on that as much as you are in
painting a propaganda against one
individual because you're afraid that
she's going to get a seat. that you're
afraid that she's gonna get on a
position that's going to be opposing
you. She is not a puppet and that's the
problem because she's not a puppet.
There's fear and then you have the
fearmongers and then you have those that
will play into your hands because it
works into your
narrative. The personal attacks need to
stop. Miss Diaz is not a racist. Miss
Diaz has been for immigrants for all and
especially the elderly. I have contacted
her again not on my own but on the
behalf of others. She didn't tell me
tell them to call me. I said to her will
you go down to this elderly building
where elderly lives that no one goes
there. No political candidate will go
there because they don't count on their
vote. They only count on a certain vote
but it's not their vote. And she went
down there and boy did that make a
difference. And she learned and she
listened to the folks there which they
had not had that. None of them have seen
a political candidate show up. That's
the kind of leadership that we need to
have here in the city. Thank you. Thank
you.
[Applause]
Our next speaker, Mr. Harris. Our next
speaker is Tony Dastra from the 700
block of New Holland Avenue. Thank you.
Mr. Dastra, good evening. Good evening.
Uh Tony Dash at 700 block of New Holland
Avenue. And I think Jess Lopez is right.
Welcome to the Janet show. Geez.
Um, so not here for that. Actually, my
comments are in regards to a different
matter. Counselors, the public deserves
answers on a matter, the legality of
rent control. I've been saying for
months now that we can do rent control.
Then at a
council then at a council debate without
foundation, candidates began saying the
state needed to act for us to do that.
Not true as far as my research goes. And
one of those candidates should know that
from our November phone call. This
misinformation finally started unfolding
at the mayoral primary debate where it
was clear where there was clearly
confusion on stage. It would seem
members of the public have started to
look into this matter as well. Here's
the deal. We can do rent control, but we
can't just do it to do it. The 1955
decision in Warren v. Philadelphia
affirms the home rule municipality's
right to rent control, but it doesn't
allow so without articulating reason.
This means we can't just say without
foundation there is a housing crisis so
we are enacting rent control. It means
we have to say something to the effect
of we are facing X conditions and as a
result of the housing crisis and so we
are implementing Y rent controls to
address this. If you're serious about
the housing crisis help us out direct
city staff to quantify and qualify our
crisis. So I'm not without nuance here.
I recognize that we have some limitation
in that regard but is not prohibitive to
the ability to authorize such action. I
keep being told that what I'm saying is
illegal and even false hope. I'm asking
for the foundation. Stop just saying
this is illegal and blaming the state.
If this is illegal, educate the public
on the matter or at least try and we
will definitely look into it. I struggle
to trust the legal opinions of the city
after the tree ordinance lost its
initial case. I'm not sure where the
status of the appeal is at this time.
The final note I'll make now is
unrelated but clearly tangential if I
had more time. I was suggested to make
an amended bill for a admin bill 3, but
really what should have been occurring
with this delay is at least one
community meeting. Public property is an
community asset and your bill doesn't
even require a final approval of sale by
council. A variation from the public
process with the plurality of our land
in the southeast quadrant. If you're
going to move forward with bill 3, it
deserves more attention and more
interface than it has gotten. When we
drafted the short-term rental ordinance,
we met with the residents of Oldtown
right here. I feel the Southeast
deserves that same respect. Table the
bill to do the right
thing. That the thing that people upset
with you are asking, you're
demonstrating that lack of care and
concern by continuing down this path.
Thank you. Thank you.
I believe Mr. Harris, we've reached the
end of the first uh the pre-registered
comment. Is that correct? We have, Madam
President. Okay. I want to go back.
There was a few people who were named
earlier who were not here at the time.
Um if uh Edri Dennison, Shannon Butler,
or Ivan Aosta wish to speak at this
time, please come forward.
Good evening. Good evening. God bless
you all and I hope I'm not insulting you
by saying God bless. Um, you see me all
like that. I just had surgery so I'm
really here because I do care. Um, I've
been accused of this too because
sometimes I say what I need to say and
I've spoken to you lots of times in
debates right to your face. Okay? And I
think one of the issues that we have is
that it easy to attack Janice. And if
you really want to defeat her, let's do
it in the election box. A lot of we come
here and let's tear people apart, you
know, and it's normal because some of
you I've told you to your faces. I
haven't hid. And my name is Ivan Acast.
I live at 804 Highland Avenue. Okay? and
you can say all you want to say and all
that, but at least I've never hit my
mom. Unless I I haven't done a lot of
things, okay? What I've done is fight
for a better city. And if she offended
you guys, I apologize because I haven't
seen her offended. She offended me one
time. She didn't bring me to
coffee. Yeah, but I I want them to see
me because I'm talking to them. Okay. I
at least The only thing she offended me,
you didn't bring me for coffee. Okay.
So, we need to get this going. And
that's for all of you because guess
what? You're gonna answer to the voters.
You're not gonna answer to Janice.
You're gonna answer to the voters. Okay?
And the voters knows what's going on. We
know what's going on. Okay? And uh one
of the things that really bothers me in
this city is that when you bring up
things that are going on right away, you
attack and and this and that and that.
You know what? Where you can attack is
the ballot box. If you're so concerned
about things that are happening, do it
at the ballot box. Reverend Bailey told
you one time at a debate we had at the
ballot box. And that's where we're doing
it. Janice, at the ballot box. Okay. And
you'll have a lot of people attacking
you. A lot of people that are sitting
there act they've said worse than you
said. And then they hide between power
and they hide between other people, you
know. But guess what? Up there there's a
man up there or a lady up there or
whatever you want to call up there.
Okay? He'll take things in the matter.
So if you want to attack people, do it
at the ballot box. That's where you do
it. Don't start doing the same thing
that the Republicans are doing and then
you say, "Oh, the Republicans are doing
it and you're doing the same thing.
Thank you."
[Applause]
Right. I believe Oh, yes, Miss Butler.
There you are.
Good evening.
Good evening. Thank you for uh giving me
this opportunity to speak in front of
you and thank you for all that you um
all that you do. This
is I went to class here. Yeah. So, this
is like my second or third time
here.
Um my
apologies. I want to read something.
Um, please do not disturb me. I don't
know who you are, but Miss Butler, don't
do that. Please continue your comments
toward council.
Janet Diaz is a well-known figure in
Lancaster, serving on the city council
since 2017 as the first Latino
elected to that position. She has built
a reputation as an independent voice and
has consistently focused on issues like
affordable housing, public safety,
healthc care access, and community
representation. Drawing from her
personal experiences with poverty and
homelessness. Pretty
sad, very
sad that a female felon with a 20-year
criminal history is used to support
uh you know this whole
uh thing that's going on. One thing I've
learned is that shame has never changed
anybody. So you you can't you can't
shame people especially when they're uh
stuck and and they just they just spew
out hate and diversion and distraction
and and all that stuff there. She is a
Langster resident with a documented
criminal history spanning roughly 15 to
20 years. Her record includes serious
convictions. She was charged with
seconddegree felonies for assaulting two
Lancaster police officers, kicking one,
hitting another with a bell, and
spitting on both, stemming from an
incident where she smashed a man's car
after a personal dispute. Her
convictions include drug
offenses, hold
on, include drug offenses, retail theft,
harassment, and in 2022, she was
convicted of a felony riot, and related
charges tied to the 2020 protest. Diaz
supporters, as you know, value her for
her honesty, transparency, and
dedication to Lancaster residents, which
aligns with her documented track record
of advocating for the underserved,
homeless, and vulnerable
community. I was going to say you all
should be ashamed, but shames never
change anybody. Shame don't change
people. Uh, like the gentleman said,
take it to the ballot. Take it to the
ballot. And
um, we have really serious issues here
in Lancaster and this uh,ler campaign
against Janet, it's it's just not cool.
Thank you, uh, Miss B. Thank you.
[Applause]
Don't believe there was one other
speaker from the first list. Edri
Dennison. Just want to confirm he's not
in the room. Okay. Uh at this point in
the meeting, we don't have a legislative
agenda. So, this is our second public
comment period open for issues not on
the agenda. Again, duration of comments
is limited to three minutes per speaker.
I am going to hold three minutes firm.
Please, if we could have decorum and
order in the room, please begin with
your name, block, or municipality of
residence for the meeting record. Thank
you, Jessica Lopez, the felon with less
felonies than our
president. So, let me start by reminding
you right that for the last five years,
I've been here more than every single
one of you in this room. So, we're user
thick today. I hope user thick in two
weeks and I hope you're thick two weeks
after that because we need support in
this community that goes way past who
sits up there. See, now the problem is
you just want to pick and choose which
disrespect is disrespectful. No, I'm
talking I'm sorry, Miss B. Y'all want to
pick and choose what disrespect is
allowed to be addressed. I've
highlighted the issues with the mayor,
with our chief of police, and yes, with
Janet Diaz, because I'm not scared of
any of you. Sorry. Yes, sir. Just like
you. Just like you. Like you didn't just
tell a Muslim woman to take off her
headdress. Miss Lopez, this is address
to council. We will have order in the
room. Now, this is the problem because
comments that she made open the door for
a white man to sit here and tell a black
woman to take off her headdress. So, I'm
the
problem. I'm the problem apparently and
not the person who took an oath to stand
for every single body. Not just the
people who came and begged her for
something. I'm sorry. This is egregious.
And for y'all to focus on me, go ahead.
I can hold that. Been doing this for
years. I walk around this city with my
head held high, unafraid of anybody.
Trust that. Trust that. And will
always and will always and will be at
the ballot box. And do come out to
community events. Work for the Lancaster
Bail Fund. work for
nonprofits. So while you sit here and
act like you know me, you don't. And I
wasn't being root or I don't speak
Spanish. Now this is the problem, the
stereotypes, the Janice show. What about
the kids that are going to court on June
6th and really need people to advocate
for
them? Those kids that were pushed off
their bikes. those kids that we came
here for originally before you turn this
into the Janice
show. Thank you. Thank you.
One moment, please. Miss Gomez, please.
For everyone in the room, I I do not
want to have to ask again. We are in the
middle of a public meeting and I wish
things to remain respectful and for us
to maintain order or I will call for an
adjournment. Thank you.
Good evening. I just talk right. I know
that a
littlehead. Good evening. Um just gonna
get right
in. Anyways, um this country was based
on lies, deception, and racism.
my people especially for over 400 years
and those in position are still looking
down at us fortunate people to fill
their deep pockets. So, excuse me guys
if you say I'm being disrespectful or my
approach is too harsh, but there are
families grieving while countless people
are dying. The city is in turmoil while
opinions are being viewed as racist.
Some may not agree with the approach.
Some may not do well with constructive
criticism, but it's still your opinion,
your God-given right to exercise freedom
of speech. Now, let me ask you, Ahmad,
is your family deprived by these words
you say you're offended by? While we
have another woman dead at Bins Park
along with many week within weeks, days
who have overdosed, lost their jobs,
suffered excessive force or abuse by
public officers, let alone deaths in our
country. uh let alone deaths in our
county prison where they don't feed
grown men or women proper meals only to
leave them and their families paying a
cost after costs that they can't even
afford while accessing bonds and
funding. Are you aware of how many city
employees, commuters, firefighters,
police officers, taxpayers, disabled
citizens in this city that have been
discriminated on, lied to along with
racial profile. This is pulled from
files. Since 2018, Lancaster has faced
legal battles showing bias against
employees, disabled residents,
firefighters, police officers, alleging
discrimination and retaliation, naming
Denine Sarra. In 2019, residents
challenged discriminatory zoning
ordinances under Denise uh Sarra's
watch. In 2021, another employee claimed
wrongful termination. This is an ongoing
issue with many lawsuits you can easily
look up. I don't know. I think she's
over 10 for
discrimination. United States versus
city of Lancaster. The determination
discriminated against on the b on the
basis of race and retaliated against
from complaining about racial
harassment. That is now when Sarra
started her journey as mayor in 2017 or
2018. Immediately these offenses took
place amongst many that were already
lined up. She underwent training to
improve her position just like Janet
will do with no endorsement from any
party but the people voted her in. Why?
Because she dares challenge the status
quo. I also challenge Janet to send me a
list of her accomplishments since she
started and I have about three pages and
I would challenge all of you to do that
if you don't mind. Thank you, Miss
Gomez. And then I'll just lastly say I'm
sorry. Um
while we I'll wrap it up while we last
thought please. While we know the bill
um given to me uh by Janet Diaz for uh
to adopt the citizens review board is it
has been opposed again by this mayor
along with other important issues Janet
presented where none of you second
it. Thank you. This is our reality.
Gomez. Thank you. Good night.
Additional
speakers. Mr. Dastra. Thank you. Good
evening. Good evening again. Tony Dash
of 700 block New Holland Avenue. Um I
don't have prepared remarks for this
session. Um but I did want to make the
remark at how odd this all is. I mean
I've never been to a council meeting
without any agenda items. Now that being
said, I do appreciate making sure
there's a record of meetings, making
sure the public's heard, all that's
good, but this is this is a bit of an
unusual circumstance. Like I maybe you
guys have been to one. And I haven't
been to every single council meeting in
the last eight plus years, but I' I've
never really seen this type of meeting
before, ever, ever. And so when Jessica
Lopez says this is the Janet show, I
really don't have any other ways because
whether you're here to support or
denounce Janet, the subject of tonight
is Janet. The news story tomorrow is
Janet. This is all
Janet. This is so weird. And the reason
it freaks me out is because we we have
other community concerns that should be
addressed. Like look, bill three is not
that long of a bill. And if
I'm if I'm explaining bill three to the
public in an inaccurate way, like the
city government should be there to be
like, "Hey, whoa, Tony is saying this,
but here's this actual process." Like
there's no back and forth here. There
there's absolute radio silence on this
side on that side of the day. seems
coming from this issue because
I I don't know what else to say but
there's a solid point to be had in some
of these remarks like Janet was the only
one who talked to me about the bills I
put in front of you regarding tax
exemptions and potentially a rebate
program
like and even to that effect when I I
appreciate the verbalization of the
willingness to create an exemption but
you're only willing to go to the extents
that you were already granted prior to
the passage of home rule. I do not
understand where like it just doesn't
make sense. It doesn't Something does
not add up here. This is not the way to
do it. People wonder why I'm not a
Democrat. And I think it's situations
like this that really demonstrate why
I've stayed away from the
party. So, thank you for your time and
attention. I hope some of this landed
with you. Have a good night. Thank you,
Mr. Dastra. Uh, just to interject really
quickly to answer a question. I would
also agree that this is an unusual
situation. Um the charter of which you
helped to draft does require two
meetings per month. So we needed to hold
this meeting and also just personally
even if it didn't um I would have wanted
to continue to have this meeting to
honor the request to speak of the people
who made the made their way to the
meeting last week. So thank you for
addressing that and that's at least part
of the reason why we're doing this. Miss
or good evening 200 block of South
Street. Um, I wasn't going to get up and
speak, but I think it's necessary. I
mean, I've never been to a council
meeting. I've been coming to council
meetings since
1989, and I've been here with a lot of
mayors and a lot I've been here when we
had split council, Democrats and
Republicans, and this is a circus. And I
think for you as a president of city
council to allow this to go on, you can
see where there's people to get to speak
over, people to get to speak out is
unacceptable. We deserve better. We
deserve better. I'm not here to speak up
for nobody. I'm here to say as our
representatives that are elected, our
council has to do better. We have
serious issues here. We just had a
preacher get up here and say about a
building that you the mayor said we
can't even give it away that asked for
it and nobody commented. You're sitting
here to hear our comments. Why didn't
you say to him we will take it into
consideration? Why didn't you say to
him, "We will think about it." You sit
there and you listen and you don't
respond and enough is enough. This was a
circus and it should not be accepted and
it should not happen again. And I'm
hoping that it doesn't and I'm hoping
that we get to the real issues because
like we said, we talking about
homelessness. We're talking about, like
I said, um, young people. We're talking
about things happening with our police.
And we had all of you sit up here and
say you saw the video and didn't like
it. But everybody stayed quiet. You
know, it's no more. It is time that the
council represents the people and it's
time that we stop letting our political
party and this this this body be a
circus. Thank you. Thank you,
Mr. Legosi. Thank you. Good evening,
Daryl Legacy, 100 block of North Mary.
Um, I just want to make two points. one,
I appreciate the statement of letting it
happen at the ballot box and I I'm sure
that council is not going to stand down.
So, I think we're all going to have
that. So, I think that's great. It's
fine. We will do that. Um, I also really
appreciated the apology that uh the
gentleman over here said. If councelor
Diaz had apologized, none of us would be
here. Nobody would be asking for this.
More importantly, I also agree with the
woman that just spoke there, if there
isn't already, there should be a rule
that no one up here speaking can
disparrage anyone in the crowd. There
also should be a rule that if people are
yelling on either side, they are
removed. This is ridiculous. This is not
how a city council meeting should work.
Um, I realize this is perhaps something
that has never happened before or not
recently. Maybe you didn't have a plan
for this, but there needs to be a plan
going forward. If anybody up here speaks
about somebody in the crowd, who is not
an elected official who has not run for
a
position, that should not be
allowed. That absolutely should not be
allowed on either side. Whatever side
you agree with, whatever side you have,
that is not something that is going to
bring this community together. I
actually think most of us want all of
the same things. I think we all want
rent control. I think we want uh a safe
city. I think there are, you know, I
think a lot of us want um restrictions
on what the police are doing. And this
is a
sideshow, but again, it should not be
community member versus community member
up here at the deis. And I really hope
that you will take this to heart and
consider some kind of rule or policy or
something that stops that from happening
again.
Thank you.
Good evening.
Hello. My name is Taylor Raymond. I live
on the 500 block of St. Joseph Street.
Um, and I'm here for something not
regarding Miss Diaz at all. Um, at
previous meetings, uh, we the
administrative resolution 18, uh, was
discussed regarding the disposition of
certain police records. We were told
that it was just the physical copies and
that digital records were being kept and
that we could request to review these
documents through the right to know act.
So, I did that. Um, on April 9th, so the
day after our last city council meeting,
I received the response on that. It was
denied
uh stating that these uh records were
subject to exception because they are
regarding criminal investigations, the
Criminal History Records Information Act
and the Juvenile Act. Um, between this
information being denied um outright
and the uh denial of any sort of open
communication with the community uh
regarding the incident that happened on
March 2nd. I really think that it is I
it's clear to me that we need a civilian
review board and we need some serious
police reform.
Thank you.
Good evening. Good evening. Thank you
for your time. My name is Ashley and
I've lived in Lancaster for the past 16
years. I'm here today to proudly support
Janet Diaz. I want to start by saying
something important. I hear your
frustration. I understand the pain.
Ashley, I'm sorry. I don't know your
last name. Could you just say your full
name for the Ashley Martinez? Sorry.
Appreciate it. Thank you. Um I
understand the pain especially from
those in the Muslim community who are
hurting right now. The injustice, the
discrimination, it's real and your anger
it's valid. But you're angry at the
wrong
person. Recently, there have been
hurtful and entirely false claims made
against Janet. Let me be absolutely
clear. That is not who Janet is. Anyone
who knows her, who's worked with her,
knows that she has spent her life
advocating for fairness, inclusion, and
opportunity for everyone in our city.
Her record speaks for itself. These
comments are not only untrue, hurtful,
but they are shameful distractions from
the real issues we face. What we should
really be talking about are the real
issues that our city is facing. Families
are being priced out of their homes. Gun
violence is affecting our neighborhoods.
Our youth are being overlooked. And
while all of that is happening, people
are wasting time attacking a woman who
has dedicated her life making this city
better. This city deserves a leader who
brings people together. Someone who
listens, leads with compassion, and
takes action. Janet is that leader.
Let's reject division and stand behind
someone who truly cares about every
resident of Lancaster. Thank you so
much. Thank you.
I just want to address Good evening. I'm
sorry. I'm sorry. Thank you for having
me back. I just want to address two
things again. My name is Asia Austin.
Two things. One, um I keep hearing a lot
of residents get up and discuss
homelessness. I just think for the
record, please, please, please, please
stop calling them homeless and please
start calling them displaced. That is
the proper term. Um, number
two, number two. Um, I was up here and I
didn't know this when I was up here
because I wasn't really listening
because I was speaking directly to all
of you.
Um to sit here and hear when I went back
there that someone is saying to me,
"Take that off your head." That is so
disrespectful. There are a lot of women
that are Muslim who do not cover up
because they are afraid.
That is scary to a woman like me. If I
wasn't as strong as I am and I was not
raised in this community like I was, I
would not have been able to handle that.
I think something needs to be said.
Something needs to be done to allow
Muslim people like me to feel
comfortable in this community. I don't
know what that would be. I don't know
what that would look like, but that is a
conversation that this council should
consider having. Thank you. Thank you.
Good evening. Good evening again. Um,
council members, community of the
members and my family that's here. Um,
lately people have been calling these
meetings the Janet show and I just heard
of that. Some say it with laughs, some
say it with frustration, but let's talk
about what that really means. Because if
this is the Janice show, it means a
woman of color standing her ground in a
place that's really not built for her.
and let it be the Janet show. Let her be
the star that she is and continues to
be. If it means growing up, speaking up,
and refusing to be silent in the face of
criticism, then yes, this is the Janet
show. So, let's be clear that phrase is
being used to minimize, to mock, and to
dismiss very real work that she has put
into this community for the past 10
years and the very real weight of what
Councilwoman Janet Diaz has carried for
this city. Now, on top of that, she's
being called
Islamophobic. And let me say this
plainly, that is not who Janet is. Like
I've expressed before, she has stood up
for immigrants from lowincome families,
for unrepresented voices, including
Muslims, in way that many people in this
room never have. Yes, a post was made.
It landed wrong, but she took
responsibility. She listened and she
opened her up. She opened herself up to
her conversations. This is what growth
looks like. Not perfection, but this is
what leadership should look
like. But instead of making space for
growth, some of us would rather come in
here and tear her down. Why? Because it
is easier to shame than to understand.
Correct? Because it is easier to label
someone than to engage with them and try
to get them get to know them better. But
I'm back here to say because I was just
up here, enough is enough. We cannot let
one moment erase a legacy. We cannot let
rumors or headlines override someone's
truth. The truth that she lives every
day and that we've seen that she lives
every day. And we absolutely cannot let
a woman's courage be turned into a
punchline. So if this is the Janet show,
then let it be a show of resilience,
representation, and real leadership.
Janet Diaz deserves our respect. Not
just us, but the whole community. She
deserves our support and she deserves
better than this. Thank you, Janet, for
everything you've done for my community.
And not just mine, but each and every
person that knocks on your door. I've
never been able to stay here and text
someone and call someone and get an
answer right away and have you come to
my house and help me fix each and every
problem that my community is facing.
There were nights that I could not sleep
because someone of my own family has
gotten deported. I did not know what to
do, how to handle that situation. you
came through and you helped and you
continue to help my community that is
full of
Hindus, Muslims and Buddhists. So for
them to come up here and say that you're
Islamic Islamophobic and all this and
that like I just I'm so sorry that that
you have to go through this and thank
you for all the support that you
continue to give us no matter the
criticism that you face. Thank you M.
I just got an operation. So that's why
I'm like this. Okay. Not that I'm scared
of you. Um my name is Ivan
Acastles. I apologize for the young lady
that said about that thing.
Yeah. I mean sometimes you don't see it.
So please I'm 65 years old. You let
other people do it. So take it back and
listen. Okay. Please. Secondly, excuse
me. Let me speak. I'm I let you speak.
Let me speak. I've come I've lived here
almost 50 years. Okay. And I was talking
to a friend in Spanish and I got an
answer that they said I should speak
English. I speak English very well
because I was an English teacher. Okay.
And I was offended and no one apologized
to me. I had to defend myself. So we
needs to stop being picky picky picky on
things. Okay? And like they say, you sit
up there and you make a lot of rules and
you do this and do that, but let's put
it to you. You do what you need to be
doing. And if you would be doing what
you need to be doing, it would be
resolved. You might you might have
whatever title you have, but that
doesn't make you special under God. What
makes you under special under God is
when you do, okay? By their fruits, by
their fruits they shall be known. Okay.
So, I apologize to the young lady that
they complain about his scar, but
there's a lot of times when I'm speaking
to someone in Spanish because they don't
understand English and they told me to
speak English. How can you speak English
to them? When I first came to work here,
I worked at the First National Bank of
Strasburg. They told me I couldn't speak
Spanish to the customers, but they
didn't speak English. So, how was I
supposed to speak to them? Okay, you can
sit there and turn your heads and do
your faces, but you know what? It'll
fall on you. And as I always say, at the
ballot box, we'll let you know.
Good evening.
Good evening, council. I'm not here to
talk about Janet. I already know her 30
years enough.
I'm here over my
concern of public parks especially uh
Crystal
Park. I don't know how many time I have
come here and told you guys that we need
some
upgrading at Crystal Park. It hasn't
been
done. We are going to open up the
summer. The West Crystal Volunteers are
opening up the summer with Mother's
Day. I cannot secure safety in my
neighborhood if the sockets, the plugs,
the wires are sticking
out. I mean that I could go
on. You need pictures or just come over.
You can see it. It's been neglected. I'm
pissed. We already have more homicides
in
Lancaster. Most of those uh shootings
has been happening up my neighborhood
and I don't accept that. Pearl Street
and all that and that was nothing like
that.
uh police officers present in the
neighborhood where they
at because they surely
not patrolling uh the hood the
neighborhood. No, they're
not. I stood at that park for 12 hours.
Not one police officer passed by
that. I'm missing a camera in that park.
I want that camera.
If all the other parks could have a
camera, we want a
camera. It's not the first time I'm
asking for this. We already paid for the
flag pole.
$600 out of our
pocket. We don't have a sign that says
the West Crystal Volunteers on it. We
want
it. I will keep coming back and I will
walk into city hall. and you don't want
to hear my move.
Thank you. Thank you.
Are there any additional comments for
this evening's
meeting? All right. Are there any
additional comments for this evening's
meeting? Now would be the
time. And just as a reminder, please
begin with your name and block of
residence for the meeting record. And
that mic can come down toward you. Thank
you. Y Okay. Okay. Thank you. My name is
Betty Jones and I live on the 200 block
of South Street and I want to say hello
to the members.
And my first response or first uh remark
I want to speak to the Islam woman and
to let her know that I do understand
because I have Muslim sisters of my own.
And I do understand what she meant about
removing her scarf because that's
important and it's sacred. It's a
religious thing for people that don't
understand.
My main subject here that I'm up here
about is the tickets that we received in
the Ann Street for
trash.
Originally I came here and I talked
about it. Darling also her and I we
talked about the tickets that were
received. Missed you told me that you
were going to take care of it. So
my question is to you has it been taken
care of or will it be taken care
of? What I'm saying when I say taken
care of looked
into what is the next steps that's going
to happen with people that receive these
tickets these
$250
tickets. Councelor Med, I know that I
was copied on these messages, so you can
go ahead and respond, Miss Jones. Okay.
Thank you, Miss Jones. And I did follow
up with the administration, um, the
mayor, uh, Council President BK, and
Director Campbell. Uh, Director Campbell
did get back to me today and said that,
um, he will get back to me on I did ask
what was the status of the tickets? Um,
were there any um uh fines that were uh
um um not waved, but you know, were they
going to be looking into any waving of
any fines? So, I am I did reach out. I'm
waiting to hear back from Director
Campbell. I did get an email from him
today, and I will follow up with you and
uh Miss Bird personally on the status of
that. I appreciate it. Thank you very
much. Thank you, Miss Jones.
Are there any additional comments for
the period?
Good evening. Good evening. My name is
Edwin. I just want to make a statement
concerning the hatred that's in this
room. I mean, if anybody here has an
idea, right, how Lancaster was founded,
we would all shut up.
all of us because every Saturday in this
town in the middle of Duke Street
there's a
clock for personal activities. They used
to hang a man of
color. If you don't have no information
about that, go to your public library or
to the newspaper. So, well, you know,
this here just sounds like a bunch of
rabbits running around eating carrots or
lettuce. I mean, if we here for Ahmad,
Miss Dia, whoever it is, like the
gentleman said, go to the ballot box.
My family been living here. I don't even
know how long. I'm 63 years old and I've
been here a long time before a lot of
you, especially you sitting up there
pretending to be council people or
whatever it is you classify yourself to
be. These are the people these are the
people that
count. They count that lady over there,
she count the Muslim lady, whoever it
is. But nobody in here is better than
nobody.
You come in here and disqualify Miss
Daddy by what she said. Please adjust
your comments for council. Thank you on
on Instagram. I mean that's ludicrous.
You going by what somebody
said or somebody post even if she did
it. Even if she did, let's say she did,
right? Does that really matter? I mean,
does that Excuse me.
Does that merely ma does that really
matter to the point where like the man
said the ballot box is going to tell it
all? We don't have to disqualify her
here and hate on her there and whatever
it is that's on your mind. The fact that
matter is that Lancaster was founded on
hate, discrimination, and murder.
Thank you for letting me share. Thank
you.
[Applause]
There any additional comments for this
period? Hearing none, we will close the
public comment period for this evening
and move on to our next items on the
agenda of which there's just a few.
Um, in the absence of a mayor's report
this evening, our next item would be the
report of president of council. I do
have a brief one to deliver. I'd like to
say this evening that I agree with many
of you who have said that it's
unfortunate that this meeting has
devolved in this
manner. It's unfortunate that this
chamber which is dedicated to service to
the community has devolved into yelling
and talking over one another.
As for the comments about decorum in
council, I would like to read directly
from resolution number 30 of 2015, which
is the current resolution that guides
our structure of the
meetings. Part it says in part, be it
further resolved that speakers
addressing city council and members of
the audience will be expected to conduct
themselves in an orderly manner and
remain respectful of others. Loud,
profane, belligerent, abusive, and
slanderous remarks will not be
tolerated. As the president of council,
it is my job to oversee these meetings,
and I am tempting to do that as best as
possible. I would expect that council
members enter this room with that in
mind, and also members of the public so
that we can continue to have productive
dialogues about the things that do
matter in this community.
But your words also matter and that's
why we had this meeting this evening and
I believe it was incredibly important to
make sure that everyone was
heard because anyone sitting in this
deis or seeking higher office in this
city is also an incredibly important
public matter in this city and people
deserve to have their say about that as
well. So I only hope that when we enter
this chamber again at our next meeting
and the meeting after that and the
meeting after that that we can continue
to have productive discussion and not
evol devolve to personal attacks in this
room. That concludes the report my
report to council this evening. Are
there any council comments this evening?
Council president if I may. Councelor
Hirs. Um, in regards to the meeting
tonight and what was discussed here,
um, I I'm I'm I'm
I'm disappointed and I'm frustrated by
by what I saw and that's all I'm going
to say because I think it does come down
to whether the individuals of the public
respect each other enough to let each
other speak. And I am frustrated that
that didn't happen
tonight. On a lighter note, I did want
to mention quickly uh that May is bike
month. If you go to
bikelancaster.com-month,
um there's a list of events that are
happening throughout the city. I just
want to shout out one in particular. Um
the ride, roll, and stroll campaign,
which is in its second or third year, um
has their launch party. It is this
Friday, uh, May 2nd at 6 PM. So, come on
out. Come on out to the city, uh, for
First Friday. Um, and maybe get to know
some of your neighbors there. Thank you.
Thank you, Councelor Hirs. Any
additional council
comments on this end of the
day hearing? None. And having concluded
the business of our meeting, I'll hear a
motion to adjurnn.
Motion to adjurnn. Second. We have a
motion and a second. All in favor? I I
We're journed. Thank you.